

CONTACT

- +91-98844 99184
- ✓ mvprem86@yahoo.com
- 11, 2nd St., Astalakshmi Ng, Porur, CH 600116, TN

EDUCATION

2023 - 2024 MADRAS UNIVERSITY

 Pursuing Master of Business Management - Logistics & Supply Chain

2006 - 2008 ANNAMALAI UNIVERSITY

- Bachelor of Marketing Mgmt.
- Grade: Third Class

KEY SKILLS

- Project Management
- Teamwork
- Procurement
- Decision Making
- Warehouse Operations
- Problem Solving
- Transportation
- Operations Management
- Leadership
- Custoamer Service
- Data Analysis
- Accountability
- International Logistics
- Critical Thinking

PREMANAND M

LOGISTICS - EXPORTS/IMPORTS

PROFILE

Customer-oriented and strategic planning entry-level supply chain specialist with over +11 years of hands-on and educational experience in data analysis, documentation, process improvements, operations, management role in warehousing in-bond/out-bond, transportation logistics environment and import/export freight forwarding air/ocean. Details-oriented and analytical logistics professional seeking organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Soft Freight Logic

Team Leader - Exports

2023 - PRESENT

- Documenting and managing the export project in Thailand and the Netherlands, as well as the import project in Canada.
- Resolving queries and problems of the team members. Guiding the team to complete their tasks.
- Regulating quarterly reviews of team members to ensure efficiency.
- Maintaining a track record of team progress and documenting the same to make an accurate report
- Guiding new SOPs to team members. Preparing Client reports on a daily and weekly basis.
- Preparing client cost validation sheet daily basis.
- Monitoring team members Booking Creation, Organization Creation, AR Invoice (Accounts Receivable), AP Invoice (Accounts Payables), Draft BL, Pre-alert, Arrival Notice, AR/AP Credit Note, DN agent overseas Invoice.

Agility Logistics (GIL Shared Services)

2017 - 2022

Senior Process Associate

- Coordinate with Shipper and consignee follow-up Shipping Docs to Draft Confirmation MBL, HBL & Supplier Docs.
- Sending the (Air/Ocean) Pre-alert Docs to the Consignee (HBL, Commercial Invoice & Packing List) Confirming the ETD & ETA Schedule to the Shipper / Consignee.
- Air/Ocean Manifestation Filing submitting to Liner & Final Agent with docs like ((Air Docs (HAWB, MAWB, Invoice, P/L & Certificate of Origin)) & Ocean Docs (MBL, HBL, Invoice, P/L & Carrier Booking Docs)) in CW1 (Cargowise One).
- Arrived Shipments should inform to Local Agent Clearing the Shipment in the respective port and inform to Consignee/CHA (Customs House Agent) for Shipment Clearances.
- Finally Prepare the Arrival Notice, Freight Cost Carrier Invoice, and Delivery Order to send to Consignee for Payment Process.

EXPERTISE

- Freight Forwarding
- Export/Import Operation
- FCL/LCL Carrier Booking
- Cost/Revenue Review
- Customer Service
 Import/Export
- Team Management

SOFTWARE

- Cargowise One
- SAP (Webcost-Finance)
- ERP GoFreight Application
- Ajira/eForms Web
 Application
- ERP Focis Application
- Control System Java
 Appplication
- SAP MM application

LANGUAGES

- English
- Tamil

WORK EXPERIENCE

Servo India Logistics

2016 - 2017

Customer Service Executive

- Preparing Vessel Sailing Schedules and arranging LCL or FCL movements based on Consignee Confirmation.
- Arranging overseas agents to release cargo vessels moving from CFS & Warehousing.
- Responsible for securing new customers and maintaining and developing existing accounts.
- Preparing Quotations and Invoices to Consignee.
- Preparing daily cargo carting reports, stuffing expenses reports, and reporting all daily activities through email to Management.

Sindhu Cargo Service Pvt Ltd

2011 - 2016

Senior Executive

- Verifying assembled orders / coordinating the work of the warehouse team.
- Sending returns back to the companies they came from / controlling warehouse operations costs / reviewing administrative records for accuracy of information and compliance with established procedures.
- Shrinks wrapping pallets and stocks / keeping the warehouse inventory current/Hiring and training up new warehouse staff.
- Completing all paperwork and admin records, managing a complex three-shift setup / Inspecting storage facilities. Reporting directly to the area manager.

AWARD

- Extra Miller Award June 2021 from GIL Shared Services (Agility Logistics)
- Best Employee Award Feburary 2015 from Sindhu Cargo Services Pvt Ltd

I hereby declare that the given particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief. Being a person with determination to succeed, I'm sure that I will be able to contribute my best to the growth of the organization.

Date:

Place: Chennai (M. PREM ANAND)